다 왔어!
All right!
와! 집에서 병원까지 7분도
안 걸렸어! 해냈어
Yes! From home to the hospital
in under seven minutes! We did it.
그래, 힘든 건 이제 다 끝났구나
Yes, the hard part is truly over.
그런 건 아니지만
시작이 좋잖아, 안 그래?
No, but come on, we're off
to a great start, aren't we?
얼마 안 걸릴 건 알았지만
이 정도면 기록이야!
I knew I'd get here fast,
but this has gotta be some kind of a record!
- 왔구나!
- 안녕
-Oh, you made it!
-Hi.
- 어떻게 우리보다 빨리 왔어?
- 택시 탔지, 걸어서 왔어?
-How the hell did you beat us here?
-We took a cab. Did you guys walk?
아니, 우리도 택시 탔어
난 연습도 여러번 했단 말이야
No, we took a cab too.
But I did test runs..
왔구나!
Hey, you made it!
이 병원에 무슨
비밀 통로라도 있는 거야?
Okay, is there some kind of magic
tunnel to this hospital?
로스, 계속 수다 떨고 있어
난 가서 애 낳을 테니까
Ross, you stay here and talk.
I'm gonna go have a baby.
알았어, 여긴 레이첼 그린이고
전 로스 겔러예요, 전화했었죠
Okay. Hi, this is Rachel Greene.
I'm Ross Geller. We called from the car.
네, 2인실을 비워놨으니
그리로 옮기시...
Right. We have a semi-private
labor room waiting for you, so..
잠깐만요, 2인실요?
1인실을 예약했는데요
Oh, whoa! I'm sorry. Semi-private?
We asked for a private room.
알아요, 그런데 원래
분만실 예약은 안 받거든요
Yes, I see that here. Unfortunately,
we can't guarantee a private room.
- 지금 1인실은 다 찼어요
- 그러게 더 빨리 오지
-And, currently, they're all unavailable.
-Man, if only you'd gotten here sooner.
죄송해요, 모두 2인실뿐이에요
I'm sorry. Semi-private rooms
are all we have.
알았어요, 잠깐만요
로스?
Okay. Just give us a second. Ross?
왜?
Yeah?
- 뇌물 먹여
- 방이 다 찼대잖아
-Give her some money.
-I really think they're out of rooms.
다 차긴, VIP한테 주려고
따로 남겨놓은 거라고
They're not, Ross. They're just
saving them for important people!
내가 대통령이라도 저럴 것 같아?
Okay? What if I was the president?
그럼 큰일 나겠지
넌 각 나라 위치도 모르잖아
Well, then, we'd be in a lot of trouble.
You don't know where any countries are.
알았어
Okay.
저기, 한번만 더 봐주시겠어요?
Say, would you mind checking again?
1인실이 좀 남아있지 않을까요?
See if any private rooms
may have opened up?
여긴 병원이에요
This is a hospital.
알았어요, 그럼
매니저 좀 불러줄래요?
Okay, I see.
Could we please talk to the manager?
여긴 매니저는 없어요
There is no manager.
간호사와 의사
그리고 2인실뿐이죠
Just nurses, doctors
and semi-private rooms.
이봐요, 당신 말투가
별로 맘에 안 드네요
Okay, you know what? I have to say,
I don't really care for your tone.
병원이 여기만 있는 게 아니라고
1인실이 없다면... 맙소사!
And this is not the only hospital in this city,
and we have no problem.. Oh, gosh!
- 왜? 왜 그래?
- 진통이야!
-What? What?
-Contraction!
- 2인실을 둘러보시겠어요?
- 네, 해될 거 없죠, 뭐
-Would you like to see a semi-private room?
-Yeah, it couldn't hurt to look.
프렌즈 시즌 8
'레이첼의 출산 - 1, 2부'
아직 2cm예요
10cm까지 열려야 돼요
Well, you're only two centimeters dilated,
and we need to get to 10.
- 좀 걸릴 거예요
- 알았어요
-It'll be a while.
-Oh, okay.
- 1시간 있다 다시 오죠
- 감사합니다
-I'll be back in an hour to check you again.
-Thank you.
닥터 롱, 뭐 좀 여쭤봐도 될까요?
Oh, wait, Dr. Long.
Can I ask you something?
사람들 말처럼
진통이 그렇게 아파요?
Is labor really as painful
as everybody says it is?
어머, 삐삐가 울리네
Oh, look at that.
My beeper's going crazy.
걱정 마, 괜찮을 거야
Hey, don't.. You know what?
You're gonna be fine.
- 좀 기다려야 되나 봐
- 그래
-I guess we have some time to kill.
-Yeah, guess so.
이것 좀 봐
Oh, check these out.
이런 건 처음 해봐
Never done this before.
좀 이상해
Doesn't feel good.
진짜 가관이다
Yeah, well, it looks great.
감사합니다
이제 침대에 가서
Thank you very much.
I think we're ready to..
전 로스예요, 두 분의 행복한 날을
망치고 있네요
Hi, I'm Ross. I'm here to ruin
this magical day for you.
아녜요, 마크 호거입니다
여긴 제 집사람 줄리죠
Oh, no, not at all. It's okay. Marc Horger.
This is my wife, Julie.
- 안녕, 저긴 레이첼이에요
- 안녕, 레이첼
-Hi, Julie. This is Rachel.
-Oh, hi, Rachel.
- 초산이에요?
- 네
-Is this your first?
-Yeah, it is.
여기 이 제이미는 우리 셋째랍니다
Well, little Jamie here is our third.
궁금한 거 있으면
주저하지 말고 물어봐요
So if you have any questions,
or you need anything at all, just holler.
- 고마우셔라
- 그러게
-That's so sweet.
-Yeah.
- 커튼을 쳐드릴게요
- 아녜요, 똑같은 처진걸요
-Let me give you guys some privacy.
-Nonsense. We're all in this together.
맞아요, 우리 매순간을
함께 나누자고요
We are gonna share every
moment of this with you.
- 아주 재미있을 것 같아요
- 맞아
-I think we're gonna have some fun.
-Yeah.
- 네, 그럼 그러죠 뭐
- 자, 웃어요!
-Oh, okay, I guess.
-Hey, smile!
- 아녜요
- 저흰...
-I don't know if..
-I really don't want any..
고마워요
Oh, thank you.
로스! 진통이 또 시작되고 있어
Oh, Ross!
Here comes another contraction.
좋아, 숨쉬어
Okay, just breathe.
- 여보, 나도 시작됐어!
- 세상에!
-Oh, honey, I think I'm having one too!
-Oh, my God!
저것 좀 봐
Hey, look at this.
- 웃어요!
- 됐어요!
-Here you go!
-Oh, no!
3시간째인데 아직도 안 나왔어
Oh, wow. Three hours and still no baby.
출산의 기적이 아니라
느림보의 기적이군
The miracle of birth
sure is a snooze-fest.
- 내가 뭐 보여줄까?
- 좋지, 뭔데?
-Hey, you wanna see something?
-Sure. What?
재밌을 거야
챈들러가 기겁하는 거 봐
This is gonna be fun.
Watch me freak out Chandler.
- 여보?
- 왜?
-Honey?
-Yeah?
내가 생각을 해봤는데
Listen, I've been doing
some thinking..
병원에 있어서 그런건지
and I don't know whether
it's because we're here..
아님 레이첼 때문인지
모르겠지만
or Rachel's giving birth..
우리도 아기 갖자
but I think we should
try to have a baby.
좋아
Okay.
방금 뭐랬어?
What's that now?
좋다고, 나도 생각해봤는데
때가 된 것 같아
Okay. I've been thinking about it too,
and I think we're ready.
농담해?
아기 가질 때가 됐다고?
Are you kidding? You think
we're ready to have a baby now?
재밌다
This is fun.
아기 가질 때가 됐다고?
이 자식 다 컸네!
You're ready to have a baby?
My boy's all grown up!
당신도 때가 됐댔잖아
You said you were ready too.
그랬지, 하지만 그건 당신이
기겁하는 걸 보려고 농담한 건데
Yeah, but I was just screwing with you
to try to get your voice all high and weird..
내가 기겁하고 있네!
Like mine is now!
아기 낳고 싶어했잖아?
Yes, but haven't you
wanted a kid, like, forever?
그렇지만, 누가 나한테
애 낳자고 한 건 처음이야
Yeah, but no one ever wanted
to have one with me. I mean..
내가 원할 때 낳을 수 있다고?
나한테 왜 이렇는 거야?
Now I'm just gonna have a baby
if I want to. Oh, what are you doing to me?
얘기 꺼내서, 미안해
I'm sorry I brought it up.
좋아, 이제 물러서!
Okay, then, back off, mister!
난 아기 가질 준비돼있어
Because I am ready to have a baby.
다만 애 아빠는 조이였으면 해
I just want Joey to be the father.
- 뭐? 미쳤어?
- 저거야! 저걸 원했다고!
-What? Are you crazy?
-That's it, right there! That's all I wanted!
미안해요, 의사가 검진 중엔
커튼을 치겠다고 우겨서요
I am sorry. The doctor insisted
on closing the curtain for the exam.
정말, 상당히 괜찮아요
Oh, that's very..
Really, very, very okay.
줄리의 자궁이 7cm 열렸어요
딱 손가락 4개 크기죠!
Julie's cervix is dilated seven
centimeters. That's about four fingers!
- 직접 만져봤어요
- 레이첼의 자궁 만져봤어요?
-Doctor let me feel it myself.
-Have you felt Rachel's cervix, Ross?
- 아뇨, 우린 그런 거 안 해요
- 우린 됐어요
-No, I don't.. We're not gonna do that.
-We won't be doing that.
원한다면 레이첼 자궁이랑
내 자궁이랑 비교해봐요
Well, if you like, you could feel Rachel's,
then feel mine to compare.
- 내가 방해했니?
- 네! 고마워요! 이따 봐
-Am I interrupting?
-Yes! Thank you! Later.
- 나 혼자 두고 가지 마
- 미안해
-No, you can't leave me alone with them.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
이리 와, 로스! 로스?
내 아인 아빠가 없어!
No, Ross? Ross? Ross?
My child has no father!
와주셔서 기뻐요, 좀 걸릴 텐데
전화드릴 걸 그랬나 봐요
I'm so glad you're here, but it's gonna
be a while. I wish you'd called first.
괜찮아, 나중에
아빠랑 다시 올게
That's all right.
I'm coming back later with your father.
- 애 낳기 전에 할 말이 있다
- 좋아요, 뭔데요?
-I needed to talk to you before the birth.
-Okay. What's up?
로스, 엄마로서 하는 말인데
Ross, I want to talk
to you as your mother..
네가 날 친한 친구처럼
생각한다는 건 알지만
even though I know that you and I
are also very close friends.
무슨 뜻인진 모르겠지만
계속 하세요
I really don't know what
you're talking about, but okay.
너한테 이걸 주고 싶구나
I brought something
that I want to give you.
네가 원할 거라 생각했어
Assuming, of course, that you want it.
엄마, 저한테 청혼하는 거예요?
Ma, you're asking me to marry you?
네 할머니 약혼 반지야
이걸 레이첼한테 주렴
This is your grandmother's engagement ring,
I want you to give it to Rachel.
- 엄마, 고마운데 됐어요
- 어서 내 말대로...
-Mom, no. Come on. Thank you.
-Just hear me out..
됐어요! 끝난 얘기라고요
No! Okay? We've been through this.
임신했다는 사실 때문에
결혼하진 않아요, 아시겠어요?
We're not gonna get married
just because she's pregnant. Okay?
로스, 술집에서 만난 아가씨와
떡방아질한 게 아니잖아
Honestly, Ross, this isn't just some girl
you picked up in a bar and humped.
엄마는 요즘 애들이
그런 말을 쓴다고 생각해요?
You think young people use
that word more than we actually do.
로스, 애한텐 가족이 있어야 돼
Ross, a child should have a family.
그 얘긴 다음에 해요, 죄송해요
You know what? I can't deal
with this right now. I'm sorry.
모니카한테 가보세요
Go.. Hey, go talk to Monica.
머리 잘랐는데 맘에 안 드실걸요
She got a new haircut.
You'll hate it.
생각해보렴, 싫다고 하면
떡방아 얘기 또 꺼낼 거야
Just think about it. If you don't,
I'll talk more about humping.
주세요
Give me.
- 안녕, 레이첼
- 안녕, 와주셔서 고마워요
-Hi, dear.
-Hi. Thank you so much for coming.
로스, 들어와!
Ross, get in here!
재밌는 거 보여줘?
You wanna see something funny?
모니카
Monica.
그만해, 또 기겁하겠어
Okay. All right, stop it.
You're freaking me out.
다시 해봐
Do it again. Do it again.
레이첼이 아길 낳았어
Hey, Rachel had the baby.
- 뭐?
- 정말?
-What?
-Really?
아니
No.
왜 재밌을 거라고 생각했나 몰라
I don't know why
I thought that'd be funny.
좀 전에 엄마 왔었는데 인사했지?
You said hi to Mom
before she left, right?
엄마 같더라니까
I thought that was her.
내가 불렀더니
머리를 확 숙이더라고
Yeah, I called her name,
and she ducked into a stairwell.
운 좋은 줄 알아
Well, you know what?
Consider yourself lucky.
날 밖으로 부르더니, 왜 레이첼과
결혼 안 하냐는 거야
She pulled me out of the labor room
to ask me why I'm not with Rachel.
- 세상에
- 짜증나겠다
-Oh, my God.
-How annoying.
그러게
Yeah.
- 왜 레이첼과 결혼 안 해?
- 농담하는 거지?
-Why aren't you with Rachel?
-You're kidding, right?
임신했다는 이유만으로
결혼할 순 없어
Look, we're not gonna be together
just because we're having this baby.
물론 심심풀이로 떡방아질한 건...
And I know she's not
just some girl I humped..
떡방아질?
Oh, humped?
참아, 로스
Come on, Ross.
그렇지만, 뭔가 운명적이잖아
But it just seems that
you two belong together.
됐어, 그런 얘기할 틈 없어
곧 애가 나온다고
Okay, stop it. I can't deal with this
right now. I have to go have a baby.
그래, 누구와 가진 애지?
Right. And with who again?
이해가 안 돼
왜 레이첼과 결혼 안 하지?
He's crazy. Why doesn't
he wanna be with Rachel?
그러게 말야
I know.
솔직히, 레이첼은 완벽하잖아
날 퇴짜 놓긴 했지만
Seriously, she's like the perfect woman.
I mean, I know she turned me down..
만약 날 받아 줬더라면
but if she hadn't
and she wanted to be with me..
레이첼을 가슴에 안고
I would take her in my arms and..
내가 이렇게 분위기 망친거
오랜만이지?
I haven't bummed you guys out
like this in a while, have I?
- 레이첼
- 어서 와
-Hey.
- 누구야?
- 새로 온 사람들
-Who's that?
-New people.
그 엽기 부부는?
What happened to the Disgustingtons?
지금쯤 애 낳았을 걸
불공평해, 내가 먼저 왔다고!
They're having their baby.
It's not fair, Ross. I got here first!
너 나간 후에 분만실로 들어갔어
Right after you left,
they wheeled her off into delivery.
자궁에 꽉 낀 제이미의 머리를
나한테 보여준 다음에 말야
Oh, but not before she gave me a nice,
juicy shot of little Jamie crowning away.
미안해
Wow. Sorry.
그래, 새로 들어온 사람들은 어때?
So how are the new people?
서로를 특이한 애칭으로 불러
Well, they have some unusual
pet names for each other.
가령 "사악한 년"이라든가
"변태 자식" 이렇게 말야
Including "Evil Bitch"
and "Sick Bastard."
- 맙소사, 진통이야
- 정말? 괜찮아, 숨쉬어
-Oh, gosh, a contraction.
-Yeah? Okay, okay. Just breathe.
- 저 여자 보는 거야?
- 아니!
-Are you looking at her?
-No!
- 딴 여자 보지 마, 변태 자식아!
- 여보, 정말 안 봤다니까!
-Don't you look at her, you sick bastard!
-Honey, I swear I wasn't looking at her!
저 여잔 진통 중이라고
그게 좋아, 이 변태 놈아?
She's in labor. You like that,
you sick son of a bitch?
커튼 좀...
I'm just gonna..
봐, 네가 쳐다보니까
저러잖아, 이 뚱보 변태야
See? It's because you were looking,
you fat pervert.
아뇨, 그런 게 절대 아니고
그냥 프라이버시 때문예요
No, no. I'm sure no one was looking.
Just want some privacy.
애인 보고 싶어?
You miss your girlfriend?
그냥 무시해
Just ignore them.
- 괜찮아?
- 그래
-You okay?
-Yeah.
- 로스
- 왜?
-Ross.
-What?
- 날 쳐다보고 있어
- 이봐!
-He's looking at me.
-Hey!
아기 얼굴도 못 보고 죽고 싶어?
You wanna live to see your baby?
입 함부로 놀리지 마
이 멍청한 자식아!
Don't you talk to my husband like that,
you stupid bastard!
맙소사! 그렇게
애가 좋으면 그냥 훔쳐!
Oh, good God! If you want
a baby so bad, just go steal it!
걱정 마세요, 이 아기들은
너무 못생겼어요
Oh, don't worry.
These babies are far too ugly for us.
왜 그래? 언제부터
애한테 푹 빠진 거야?
What is going on with you.
Since when are you so crazy about babies?
애한테 빠진 게 아냐
우리한테 빠졌지
I'm not crazy about babies.
I'm crazy about us.
뭐?
What?
당장은 아니더라도
언젠간 애 가질 생각했었잖아
We've always talked about having
babies someday, not now..
그런데 지금도 괜찮을 것 같아
우리 잘 지내잖아
but I'm starting to think that we
can handle it. We're good.
아주 잘 지내지
We're really good.
꽤 잘 지내지
We are pretty good.
그렇다고 강요는 안 해
자기가 준비될 때까지
But nothing has to happen
until you're ready.
나 준비된 거 같아
Well, maybe I'm ready now.
좀 겁나긴 하지만
때가 됐는지 누가 알아
I mean, it's a little scary,
but maybe it's right.
뭐? 그렇지 않아!
우린 준비가 안 됐다고!
What? It's not right!
We're not ready to have a kid now!
- 뭐?
- 농담이야, 이거 재밌네
-What?
-I'm kidding. This is gonna be fun.
그럼 시도하는 거야?
정말 시도해?
So we're gonna try?
I mean, we're trying?
시도해야지
We're trying to get pregnant.
애들 앞에서 이러긴 좀 그러네
I'm not comfortable doing
this in front of the babies.
- 언제 시작할까?
- 잠깐만
-So when do you want to start trying?
-All right, hold on a sec.
- 월경 계산해?
- 응
-Period math?
-Yeah.
계산해 봤는데 지금인 것 같아
Well, we could start trying now.
- 여기서?
- 아니
-Right here?
-No, not here.
어쩌면
Maybe here.
완벽해, 시간도 많겠다
여기 침대도 가득하잖아!
It's perfect. We got a lot of time to kill,
and we're in a building that's full of beds!
또 깨끗하기까지 해!
And it's so clean!
이 멍청한 놈! 뱉어내!
Come on, you stupid machine! Come on!
- 네 돈 삼켰어?
- 아니
-It ate your money?
-No.
- 먼저 내려갈게
- 그래
-I'll see you downstairs then.
-All right.
나왔다! 만세!
Hey, I got one! I got one!
- 안녕
-Hi.
- 위요? 아래요?
- 아래요
-Oh, up or down?
-Oh. Down, please.
자존심 뭉개긴 싫지만
제가 해도 돼요?
I hate to be a ball-buster,
but can I just do it?
- 위층도 눌러줄래요?
- 물론이죠
-Could you press up too?
-Sure.
- 저도 다리 부러진 적이 있어요
- 그래요? 어쩌다가요?
-I feel bad. I broke my leg once too.
-Yeah? How'd yours happen?
얘기하자면 긴 데다
좀 창피해요
Well, it's a long story,
it's kind of embarrassing.
그냥 섹스 매뉴얼과 관련된
인쇄상 오류였다고 해두죠
Let's just say there was a
typographical error with a sex manual.
- 당신은요?
- 교통 사고예요
-How about you?
-Car accident.
어떤 멍청이가 휴대폰 들고
운전했어요?
Some idiot on a cell phone
wasn't paying attention?
맞아요, 저요
Yeah. Me.
- 죄송해요
- 아녜요, 괜찮아요
-Sorry.
-Oh, no. No, don't be.
다친 사람은 없었죠
운이 좋았어요
Nobody else got hurt.
And I was pretty lucky.
무사하니 다행이네요
Well, I, for one, am glad you made it.
정말요? 날 알지도
못하잖아요
Are you sure?
I mean, you don't know me.
지구를 파괴하러 온
외계인일 수도 있어요
I could have been sent
from another planet to destroy Earth.
버튼도 못 누르잖아요
지구는 무사할 거예요
Couldn't press the "down" button.
I think Earth's okay.
갈게요
Oh, hey, that's me.
누구 병 문안 왔나 봐요?
Hey, I take it you're
just visiting someone.
시간 있으면, 다른 사람
문안도 하겠어요?
Well, if you have some time
and you wanna visit someone else..
그럴게요
Yeah, I would like that.
- 좋아요, 내 병실은...
- 잠깐! 안 돼! 문 열어!
-Great. I'm in room..
-Wait! What? No! Elevator! No!
버튼을 눌러야 돼
You gotta press the button.
간호사 말이 또 새로 들어온대
The nurse said
they're bringing in another woman.
임신은 했대?
Oh. Is she pregnant yet?
아직 안 했어도 상관없어
그래도 나보다 먼저 낳을테니까
She doesn't need to be.
She'll still have the baby before I do.
- 로스! 또 진통이야
- 알았어, 잡아
-Oh, Ross! Another contraction.
-Oh, okay. Here, here.
그렇지
That's it.
- 무지 아픈가 보네
- 맞아요
-Oh, that sounded like a bad one.
-Yeah, it was.
난 별로 안 아파요
진통이 또 시작됐어
Mine haven't been so bad.
Oh, here comes one now.
엄청 아팠어
Oh, that was a big one.
이렇게 아파하는 건 처음 봐요
괜찮아, 자기?
That was, like, the biggest one yet.
Are you okay, honey?
괜찮아
I'm okay, honey.
듣기 싫겠지만
통증은 심해질 거예요
Well, I got some bad news.
It gets worse.
그러다 마지막 순간에 도달하면
And when you get to the end,
they get really big..
1분마다 엄청 아프죠
and they come, like, every minute.
난 낳을 때가 된 것 같아요
내 생각엔
Well, mine are pretty close together.
I think..
- 실례했어요
- 괜찮아요
-Excuse me.
-Yeah, that's quite all right.
난 요하나예요, 이름이 뭐죠?
Oh, by the way, my name's Johanna.
What's yours?
실례합니다
좀 도와주시겠어요?
Excuse me, could you help me
with something?
남자를 찾고 있어요
I'm looking for a man.
누군들 아니겠어?
Well, who isn't?
당신은 아니군요
You. You aren't.
좋으시겠어요
Good for you.
어쨌든 다리가 부러진
환자예요
Anyway, the patient
I'm looking for has a broken leg.
휠체어를 타는 30대 초 중반의
아주 매력적인 남자죠
He's in a wheelchair. He's early
to mid-30s, very attractive.
당신이라도 그렇게 생각할 걸요
Even you would think so.
- 누군지 알겠어요
- 잘됐군요! 몇 호실이죠?
-I know who you're talking about.
-Great! What room number is he in?
미안하지만 환자 신상은
병원 기밀이에요
I'm sorry.
Patient information is confidential.
그 남자를 성가시게
하려는 게 아니라...
No, I'm not gonna bother him.
We were talking earlier..
이봐요, 안됐지만 환자 신상은
직원들만 알게 돼있어요
Ma'am, I'm sorry. That information
is restricted to hospital staff.
- 닥터 드레이크 르모레이오
- 드레이크 누구요?
-She's with me. Dr. Drake Ramoray.
-Dr. Drake who?
르모레이요, 포르투갈어요
환자 신상 정보가 필요하오
Ramoray. It's Portuguese.
We need that information. I'm a doctor.
- 이 병원 의사라고요?
- 젠장, 시간을 낭비하고 있군
-A doctor at this hospital?
-Damn it, we're losing precious time.
이 환자 꿀꺽하는 거 보고 싶소?
You want this man's blood
on your head..?
- 꼴까닥이야
- 꼴까닥!
-Hands.
-Hands!
지금 당장 내 비서에게
병실 번호를 가르쳐주시오
It is absolutely essential that you tell me
what room he is staying in.
그 사람은 오랫동안 내 환자였소
He's a patient of mine.
I've treated him for years.
- 816호실이에요
- 816호실, 고맙소
-He's in room 816.
-816. Thank you.
- 환자 이름이 뭐요?
- 됐어
-And what is his name?
-No.
- 여기가 좋겠어
- 좋아
-I think we found a place.
-Okay.
잠깐, 무드를 조성해야지 않아?
Wait. Wanna set the mood a little?
안녕, 모니카
Hello, Monica.
- 그런 거 말고
- 알았어
-Not like that.
-Oh, okay.
- 불을 흐리게 할게
- 좋아
-We'll dim the lights.
-Okay.
아니면 다 끄는 것도 괜찮고
Or turn them out altogether.
향초는 없고
그렇지, 이걸 뿌려줄게
No scented candles.
Okay, here. There we go.
됐어, 그러다 난자까지 죽겠어
Okay, okay.
Making me sterile, but okay.
좋아, 잠깐만
콘돔 가져왔어?
Okay. I'm sorry. Oh, wait.
Do we have a condom?
그렇지 참!
Oh, right!
37도군요, 아무 이상 없습니다
Yes, 98.6. You're gonna be fine.
저기야!
This is it!
- 그 남자야!
- 잘됐네, 들어가 봐!
-That's him!
-Great. Go get him!
잠깐만, 네가 먼저 들어가 봐
Wait a second.
Or maybe you could go in first.
내 스타일 아냐
He's not really my type.
그게 아니라 의사인 척하고
들어가서 얘길 해보라고
Not you. Dr. Ramoray. Ask him
questions and see what he's like.
- 의사한텐 다 말하잖아
- 멋진 남자라며
-People tell doctors everything.
-You said he was this great guy.
처음 만날 때 그렇다가도
다들 이상하게 변한단 말야
All the guys I meet seem nice at first,
then turn out to be big jerks.
- 그런 놈만 좋아해서 그래
- 나도 알아
-You do attract some stinkers.
-Yeah, I know.
닥터 롱, 벌써 17시간째라고요
Dr. Long, I've been at this
for 17 hours.
여자 셋이 들어왔다
아일 낳고 돌아갔어요
Three women have come
and gone with their babies.
제발 희망 좀 주세요
몇 센티나 열렸죠? 8? 9?
You gotta give me good news. How many
centimeters am I dilated? Eight? Nine?
- 3cm요
- 3cm요?
-Three.
-Just three?
저도 3cm는 돼요!
I'm dilated three!
느리지만 진행되고 있어요
걱정 말아요, 잘하고 있으니까
We are moving along just slowly.
Don't worry, you're doing great.
- 곧 다시 올게요
- 감사합니다
-I'll be back soon.
-Thank you.
더 이상은 못 기다려
그냥 아길 밀어낼 거야
You know what? I'm not waiting.
I'm gonna push this baby out.
정말 한다고, 3cm라잖아
그럼 이 정도쯤 되겠지?
I'm doing it. Three centimeters.
That's gotta be like this, right?
- 이 정도에 더 가깝지
- 미터법은 엉터리야
-Actually, it's more like this.
-Oh, stupid metric system.
이대로 분만실로 가야겠습니다
We're gonna need to take you straight
to the delivery room.
축복 받았군!
Oh, for the love of God!
나와요! 나온다고요!
It's coming! It's coming!
나왔어요!
And here it is!
못 살아!
Oh, come on!
닥터 드레이크입니다
몇 가지 질문 좀 하려고요
I'm Dr. Drake Ramoray. I have a few
routine questions I need to ask you.
제 담당의사는 닥터 웰스인데요
Really? I've been dealing with Dr. Wells.
알아요, 전 신경과 의사죠
확실하자는 차원에서
I know. I'm a neurologist.
Just to be on the safe side..
그 놈이 총체적인 걸 봐달라고
저한테 부탁을 했어요
Dr. Wells wanted a more
comprehensive overview. So he sent me.
닥터 웰스는 여자예요!
Dr. Wells is a woman!
테스트였어요, 아주 잘했어요
That was a test. Good response.
- 좋아요, 이름이 뭐죠?
- 클리포드 버넷이오
-All right. Full name?
-Clifford Burnett.
- 생년월일?
- 1968년 11월 16일
-Date of birth?
-November 16, 1968.
나이?
Age?
- 계산할 줄 모르세요?
- 난 의사지 수학자가 아녜요
-Can't you figure that out?
-I'm a doctor, not a mathematician.
- 33살이오
- 좋아요
-I'm 33.
-Okay.
- 결혼했나요?
- 아뇨
-And are you married?
-No.
그래요? 33살인데 독신이라
혹시 속박이 두려운 건가요?
Oh, really? So 33 and single? Would
you say you have commitment issues?
질문이 다 그렇게 개인적인가요?
Are all the questions this personal?
그래요
Yes.
꼭 알아야겠다면, 상처했습니다
Well, if you must know, I'm a widower.
- 정말 안됐군요
- 그래요
-Oh, that's terrible. I'm really sorry.
-Yeah.
집사람은 5년 전
심근경색으로 사망했죠
I lost my wife five years ago
to a mild cardial infarction.
- 심장마비요
- 네, 압니다, 심신...
-A heart attack, doctor.
-Oh, yeah. Well, yeah, mild car..
혹시 현기증 같은 거 있나요?
Are you experiencing any dizziness?
아뇨
No.
- 통증이 악화되나요?
- 아뇨
-Has the pain been getting worse?
-No.
하룻밤 사랑 같은 걸 즐기나요?
Do you sleep with women
and never call them again?
- 아뇨
- 좋아요, 아주 좋아
-No.
-Excellent. Excellent.
마지막 질문입니다
성적으로 괴상한 걸 즐기나요?
And finally, are you into any weird
stuff, you know, sexually?
- 아뇨!
- 답이 틀렸어요
-No!
-Wrong answer.
- 이 방이 비었네요
- 잠깐! 내 말 잘 들어요!
-This room's available.
-Okay! Wait, you listen to me!
나 여기서 기다리는 동안
4명이
Since I have been waiting,
four women..
내 자궁이 열린 것보다
하나 더 많은 4명이
that's four, one higher than
the number of centimeters I'm dilated..
아길 낳았어요, 이젠 내 차례라고요
그게 공평해요
have come and gone with their babies.
I'm next. It's my turn. It's only fair.
나보다 먼저 출산할 산모를
또 데리고 오면 고소할 거예요
If you bring in one more woman who has
her baby before me, I will sue you.
병원이 아니라 당신을요
우리 남편이 변호사라고요
Not this hospital. I'm gonna sue you.
My husband is a lawyer.
- 레이첼?
- 고소할 준비해, 여보!
-Rach?
-You get back on that case, honey!
이번 산모는 오래 걸리지
않을 거예요
I don't think the next
patient is very far along.
좋아요, 그럼
데려오도록 하세요
Okay. Well, then bring her in.
소사 소사 맙소사!
Oh, my God!
믿을 수가 없어!
I can't believe this!
그런데도 사실이니
이걸 어쩌나
And yet, somehow, it's true.
너무 멋져, 이제 우린
출산 동기동창이라고
I mean, this is so great.
We're gonna be baby buddies!
허벅지 꽉 조여서 애 귀를 막아
Squeeze your legs together
and cover the baby's ears.
- 안녕, 여보!
- 안녕, 자기야
-Hi, sweetie!
-Hi, sweetheart.
우리 남편 시드야, 처음 보지?
로스, 레이첼, 여긴 시드야
This is my husband, Sid. I don't think
you've met him. Ross, Rachel, this is Sid.
1년 전 피부과에 갔다 낚아챘어
I nabbed him a year ago
at the dermatologist's office.
여드름 덕을 봤지 뭐!
Thank God for adult acne!
너무 꿈만 같아요
전 진짜 행운아라니까요
I still can't believe it.
I'm the luckiest guy in the world.
정말요?
Really?
뭐래?
What'd he say?
크게 말해야 돼
귀가 거의 안 들리거든
You have to speak very loudly,
he's almost completely deaf.
- 그렇구나
- 그럼 그렇지
-Oh, there you go.
-Of course he is.
두 사람 축하해!
둘이 결혼한 줄 몰랐어
Congratulations, you two.
I didn't even know you got married.
- 결혼 안 했어
- 뭐?
-Oh, we didn't.
-What?
그냥 애만 같이 낳는 거야
그것 말곤 없어
We're just having this baby together,
but that's all, you know.
왜?
Why?
그냥 맘이 그렇거든
하지만 애 가진 건 행복해
We're just not in that place, you know?
But we're very excited about this.
그럼 나 입다물고 있어야겠네
Oh. Well, then shut me up.
그게 될까?
Just tell me how.
진통이 다시 시작됐어
Oh, I feel another one coming.
귀먹은 자식, 넌 행운아야
Sid, you lucky, deaf bastard.
- 그리고 또?
- 나이는 33살
-What else? What else?
-He's 33.
상처했대
A widower.
괜찮은 남자인 것 같아
참, 변태 짓은 안 한대
He seemed like a standup guy.
And he's not into anything weird sexually.
나 입장할게!
Enter Phoebe!
바로 옆에 텅빈 1인실이
있다고 얘기해줄까?
Should we tell Rachel there's an empty
private room right next door to hers?
글쎄, 말 안하고
우리가 써도 되지
We could. Or we could have sex in it.
바지 벗는 동안 생각해볼게!
Well, let me think about that
while I remove my pants!
좋아! 씨 뿌려!
Okay, mister! Fertilize me!
재니스 소리 같지 않아?
Does that sound like Janice?
아니면, 쌍둥이가 있는거야
If it's not, then there's two of them.
만약 그렇담 세상의 종말이야!
And that would mean
it's the end of the world!
안녕
Hey.
- 어서 와
- 안녕
-Hey.
-Hi.
왜 이렇게 오래 걸리는지
모르겠어, 좀 어때?
I can't believe this is taking so long.
How you doing?
괜찮아, 큰 개가 엉덩이에서
나오려는 기분 알아?
Not bad. You know that feeling, trying
to blow a Saint Bernard out your ass?
조금 있으면 누군가가
"엄마"라고 부를텐데
And soon someone will call her "Mom."
이상한 일이 있었어, 혹시...
Weirdest thing. Did I hear..?
맙소사, 진짜잖아!
Mother of God, it's true!
챈들러 빙!
Chandler Bing!
재니스
Janice.
그냥 재니스가 아니라
진통을 겪고 있는 재니스야
Not just Janice. Janice in labor.
Contracting and everything.
이런 건 쉬워, 난 골반이 넓거든
Oh, this should be easy.
I have a very wide pelvis.
기억 하지, 챈들러?
You remember, Chandler.
자기 참 안됐다
I feel so bad for you.
자기 옛날 애인이잖아
난 리처드가 있는데
She's your ex. And I have Richard.
재니스, 임신한 거 전혀 몰랐어
Janice, I didn't even know
you were pregnant.
당신한테 씨를 빼앗긴
멍청한 인간이 누구야?
Who's the unwitting human
whose essence you've stolen?
자기
It's you.
자기 애야
This is yours.
뭐?
What?
긴장하는 것 좀 봐!
우리가 헤어진 게 언젠데!
Look how nervous he gets!
We haven't slept together in years!
재미있네, 아파? 진통이 아파?
That's funny. Does it hurt?
Does the labor hurt?
좋아요, 대답해봐요
꼭 먹어야 한다면 뭘 먹을래요?
Okay, I've got one for you.
If you had to, which would you eat?
맹도견? 아니면 말하는 고릴라?
A Seeing Eye dog or a talking gorilla?
말하는 고릴라가 나을 것 같아요
I'd have to say the talking gorilla.
잡아먹게 만든 건 당신이라는
얘길 해줄 수 있잖아요
Because at least I could explain to him
that you're making me eat him.
- 대학 나온 사람 있네요
- 맞아요
-Oh. Somebody went to college.
-Yeah.
왜 그래요? 미안해요
Wow. What is it? I'm sorry.
아녜요, 발이 너무 가려워서요
I'm sorry. My foot itches like crazy.
긁어줄게요
Oh. I'll get it.
보통땐 여자를 충분히 안 후에
내 몸을 만지게 하는데
I usually get to know a girl better
before I let her spoon me.
긴장 풀어요, 포크도 아닌데 뭐
Relax. It's not like we're forking.
됐어요, 그만
When. When.
고마워요, 저기 말예요
Thank you. Listen.
식기를 사용할 줄 아는 것 같군요
You seem to really know
what to do with a utensil.
언제 같이 저녁 하겠어요?
Would you like to go to dinner sometime?
- 네, 좋아요
- 정말?
-Yeah, I'd really like that.
-Yeah?
네, 개나 고릴라 요리를
먹으라는 얘긴 안 할게요
Yeah. And I promise I won't make
you eat any remarkable animals.
저기 말예요
I was thinking..
가까이 갔으면 좋겠는데
I'd kind of like to make a move.
다리 때문에
But, you know, with the leg.
네
Oh, yeah.
도와줄래요?
Maybe a little help.
좋아요
Okay.
베개 고쳐줄게요
Let me fix your pillow.
너무 앞서가네요
Cliff, you're so forward.
만나서 반가웠어요
Oh, it was really nice meeting you.
시드!
Sid!
재니스 목소린 처음 들어봐요
That's the first time I heard her voice.
별로네요
I didn't care for it.
5명째야, 로스
5명이 5명을 낳았는데
Oh, that's five, Ross.
Five women have had five babies..
난 1명도 없다고
and I have had no babies.
왜 안 나오려 하지?
Why doesn't she want to come out?
왜 그런지 알아?
네가 지난 9개월 동안
You know what I think it is?
I think you made such a nice home for her..
너무 잘 보살펴줘서
나오기가 싫은 거야
over the last nine months
that she just doesn't want to leave.
날 위해 헛소리 지어낸 것
좀 봐
Oh, look at you making up crap for me.
- 맙소사
- 좋아, 자
-Oh, God.
-Okay. Okay.
21시간째예요, 정말 장하네요
Twenty-one hours. You're a hero.
어떻게 좀 해보세요!
약을 주던가 아니면
Doctor, you gotta do something!
Get me drugs..
연기를 피워 밖으로
유인하든지요!
or light a fire up in there
and just smoke it out!
사실은 분만실로 갈 시간이 됐어요
Actually, I think you're ready to go
to the delivery room.
네?
What?
10cm예요
이제 엄마가 되는 거예요
Ten centimeters.
You're about to become a mom.
세상에, 좋아요
Oh, my God. Okay.
내가 이겼지!
아가야
Beat you, sucker! Oh, baby.
내 발 긁을 때 쓴 숟가락이에요?
Is this the same spoon
that was in my cast?
있잖아요
You know what?
이거예요
This one is.
이럴 수가! 저 의사 아까
내 방에 왔었어요
Oh, my God! That's the doctor
who was in my room before.
병원 CCTV 카메라인가 보네요
Well, it must be one of those
closed-circuit hospital channels.
아녜요, 드라마예요
No, no. That's a soap opera.
이 병원이 상당히 드라마틱해요
This is a very dramatic hospital.
정말이에요, 저 드라마에
나온 남자가 들어와서
I'm telling you,
the guy from that show was here..
나한테 이상한 질문을 했다고요
asking me all these weird questions.
알았어요, 마취제
Okay, Mr. Percocet.
진짜 저 남자가
확실하다니까요
I swear to you, that's the guy.
좋아요, 클리프
Okay, Cliff.
드라마에 나오는 인물이
정말 여기 왔다고 생각해요?
Do you really believe that a character
from a TV show was here in your room?
드라마를 보다 잠이 들어
꿈을 꾼 건지도 모르잖아요
What probably happened was you were
watching this, you drifted off to sleep..
꿈과 헷갈리는 거예요
and you dreamt he was here.
레이첼이 분만실로 갔어!
Rachel's having her baby!
신경과 의사인 저완 상관이 없죠
Which is of no interest
to me as a neurologist. I..
저 남자라고요! 아는 사이에요?
That's him! You know him?
잠 깨요, 클리프!
Wake up, Cliff!
어떻게 된 거죠?
What is going on?
좋아요, 좋아, 알았어요
Okay. Okay. I.. Okay.
제 친구 조이를 보내
당신에 대해 알아본 거예요
I sent my friend, Joey,
in here to find out stuff about you.
결과가 잘 나왔죠, 칭찬이에요
If it.. You know, if it helps,
you came off great.
지금의 저보다 훨씬 멋있더군요
A lot better than I'm coming off
right now.
말도 안 돼, 친구한테
가짜 의사 노릇을 시켜요?
I don't believe this. You got him
to pretend he was a fake doctor?
가짜라니? 이봐요
Fake? Excuse me? Hello?
- 그리곤 날 미쳤다고 해요?
- 잘못했어요, 사과할게요
-You tried making me think I was crazy?
-That was wrong. I'm so sorry.
당신이 좋아서 그랬어요
다시 시작하면 안 돼요?
It's just that I liked you so much.
Can we just start over?
됐어요
I don't think so.
잠깐만요, 당신 얘길 나한테
많이 해줬잖아요, 그렇죠?
If I may? You told me a lot
of personal stuff about you, right?
이제 피비 얘길 해줄게요
그럼 서로 비긴 게 될 테니까
Now, maybe it would help if you knew
some personal stuff about her.
피비는 게이 아이스 댄서랑
결혼한 적이 있고
She was married to a gay ice dancer.
남동생한테 세 쌍둥이를 낳아줬죠
She gave birth to her
brother's triplets.
피비의 쌍둥이 언니는
포르노 배우였어요
Her twin sister used to do porn.
- 조이, 지금은 수습할 때야
- 맞아
-We're trying to dial down the crazy.
-Right.
우린 아직 서로를 잘 모르니까
없었던 일로 하기 쉽겠죠
We don't really know each other,
so it'd be easy to forget about this..
하지만 서로 끌렸잖아요
당신한텐 어떤지 몰라도
but there's something between us.
I don't know about you..
나한텐 자주 있는 일이 아녜요
but that doesn't happen to me a lot.
- 나한테도 그래요
- 나한테도요!
-It doesn't happen to me either.
-Me neither!
- 레이첼한테 가봐!
- 그렇지 참!
-The baby! Rachel!
-Right, right!
이 장면 멋져
Oh, I love this scene.
나도 가봐야 돼요
Okay, look. I gotta go too.
저녁 같이 먹지 않을래요?
But.. What do you say?
Can we just have that dinner?
세 쌍둥이 말예요
The triplets.
설마 남동생과 실제로...
You and your brother didn't..?
아녜요! 그건 인공 수정한 거예요
No! No, they implanted embryos.
- 그럼 저녁 같이 먹어요
- 만세! 좋아요
-Then dinner sounds great.
-Great! Okay.
그럼 나중에 올게요
All right, then I'll see you later.
친구가 애를 낳아요
Our friend's having a baby.
- 아빠도 있고요?
- 그럼요
-Her own?
-Oh, yeah. Yeah.
걔가 얼마나 보수적인데요
No, she's really old-fashioned.
힘 줘요, 힘 줘
5초 동안 힘주는 거예요
Push. Push. We're gonna push
for five more seconds.
다섯, 넷...
Five, four..
셋, 둘, 하나!
Three, two, one! Oh!
다음 번엔 20초간 힘 줘야 돼요
The next contraction should be
in about 20 seconds.
- 더는 못하겠어요!
- 아주 잘하고 있어
-I can't push anymore!
-You're doing great.
맙소사! 20초라니 차라리 죽여!
Oh, God! Twenty seconds, my ass!
좋아요, 계속 힘 줘요
Here we go. Okay, keep pushing.
- 힘 줘
- 힘 줘요, 잠깐만
-Come on.
-Push. Wait.
- 뭔가 보여요
- 그래요? 정말요? 맙소사!
-I see something.
-What, you do? You do? Oh, my God!
- "맙소사!" 하지 마, 뭔데?
- 이게 뭐죠?
-Don't say "Oh, my God!" What?!
-What is that?
아기 엉덩이요, 위치가 거꾸로예요
The baby's buttocks. She's breech.
- 난 또 머리가 둘인 줄 알았죠
- 맙소사!
-I thought she had two heads.
-Oh, God!
괜찮을까요?
Is she gonna be okay?
- 괜찮아요
- 걱정 마
-She's gonna be fine.
-Okay.
위치가 별로 안 좋으니
더 힘껏 밀어야 돼요
She's in a more difficult position,
so you have to push harder now.
- 알았어요
- 그렇지, 힘 줘, 힘 줘
-Okay.
-That's it. Push. Push.
레이첼, 힘을 더 세게 줘야 돼요
You're gonna have to push even harder.
- 미안해요, 더는 못해요!
- 할 수 있어, 난 널 믿어
-I'm sorry, I can't! I can't!
-Yes, you can. I know you can do this.
더는 못해, 네가 대신 해줘!
I had no idea.
Please, you do it for me!
힘내, 이번이 마지막이야
준비됐어? 하나, 둘, 셋
Let's go. One more time.
One final push. Ready? One, two, three.
좋아요
Good.
계속 힘 줘!
Keep pushing!
괜찮아?
Are you okay?
얼마나 아픈지 상상도 못할 거야
You have no idea how much this hurts.
힘 줘! 어서!
Keep going! Keep going!
됐어요!
Here we go!
엎드려있긴 하지만 나오고 있어!
She's upside down, but she's coming!
- 맙소사!
- 세상에!
-Oh, God!
-Oh! Oh, my God!
세상에, 애가 나왔어
Oh, my God, she's here.
완벽해
Oh, she's perfect.
너무 작아
Oh, wow! Oh, she's so tiny.
- 어디 가는 거야?
- 담요를 둘러야지
-Where'd she go?
-They're just wrapping her up.
조심하세요, 애가 너무 작아요
Okay. Well, be careful with her,
she's really tiny.
여기 있어요
Here she is.
나와줘서 고맙다
Oh, thanks for coming out of me.
알아
I know. Oh.
날 보고 있어
안녕, 우리 예쁜이구나
She's looking at me. Hi. I know you.
- 이름은 지었어요?
- 아뇨, 아직요
-Do we have a name yet?
-No, not yet.
좋아요, 그럼 당분간
그린이라고 부르죠
That's fine. For now we'll just
call her Baby Girl Greene.
아뇨, 겔러 그린이에요
Oh, no. Baby Girl Geller-Greene.
안녕, 아가야
Hello, Baby Girl.
- 들어가도 돼?
- 들어와
-Can we come in?
-Oh, come on in.
- 아기야
- 정말 예쁘다
-Oh, there she is.
-Oh, she's so beautiful.
안아봐
Here.
세상에, 너무 예뻐
Oh, my God. She's amazing.
둘이 술 취해 섹스하길 잘했어
Oh, I'm so glad you guys got drunk
and had sex.
신기해, 네 몸 속에
들어갈 땐 1분 걸렸는데
It's incredible. I mean,
one minute she's inside you..
나올 땐 47시간이나 걸렸잖아
and then 47 hours later,
here she is.
진짜 같아
She looks so real.
무슨 뜻인지 알잖아
You know what I mean.
몸집만 작지 완전 사람이라고
She's this whole tiny little person.
벌써 속눈썹도 있고 무릎에다
And she already has eyelashes
and knees and..
- 왜?
- 아냐
-What?
-Oh, no, no. It's okay.
잠시 손가락이 6개인가 했는데
하나는 다른 손 손가락이었어
For a second, I counted six fingers, but one
was from the other hand. So we're good.
- 좋아, 내 차례야
- 피비 이모란다
-Okay, my turn. My turn.
-Aunt Phoebe.
아가, 어쩌면 귀엽기도 해라!
Oh, baby. Oh, you're so cute!
콱 깨물어 버릴까 보다
Oh, I could squeeze your little head.
안 해
I won't.
- 왜 그래?
- 그냥 자꾸 눈물이 나
-Honey, what's the matter?
-Nothing. I just can't stop crying.
의사 말이 정상이래, 호르몬이랑
수면 부족때문에 그렇대
The doctor said it's normal, with all
the hormones, plus you're sleep-deprived.
잠 못 자긴 다 마찬가진데 뭐
So. You guys are all sleep-deprived.
니들은 슬리퍼 잘못 신었다고
울지 않잖아
I don't see you weeping because you
put your slippers on the wrong feet.
세상에
Oh, God.
- 또 왜 그래?
- 짝짝이 슬리퍼가 생각나서
-What's the matter now?
-I was reliving it.
아기 이름은 지었어?
Do you know what you're gonna
call her yet?
잠깐만, 그냥 아기 아냐?
특이하고 좋잖아
Wait, it's not gonna be Baby Girl?
I thought that was so original.
두 가지 이름으로 압축이 됐어
Actually, we've narrowed it
down to two names.
난 다 좋으니까 네가 골라
그냥 그걸로 부르지 뭐
And you know what? I love them both.
So just pick one, and that'll be it.
좋아, 얘들아
Wow, okay. Everyone..
이사벨라를 소개할게
this is lsabella.
- 안녕, 이사벨라!
- 안녕
-Hi, lsabella!
-Hi.
왜?
What?
그건 얘 이름이 아냐
That's not her name.
미안한데 이사벨라처럼
생기질 않았다고
I'm sorry, she just doesn't feel
like an lsabella.
그럼 퍼디난드도 물 건너갔군
So then I guess Ferdinand is out.
- 다른 건 뭔데?
- 데릴라
-What was the other one?
-Delilah.
잘한다! 자기 딸을
성경 속의 창녀로 만들었어
Oh, great! Suddenly she
sounds like a biblical whore.
싫으면 그냥 아기라고 부르던가
So I guess we're back to Baby Girl.
뭘로 하지?
What are we gonna do?
- 걱정 마, 곧 생각날 거야
- 너한텐 쉽겠지
-It's okay. You'll find a name.
-Easy for you to say.
이미 애 이름을 정해놨으니까
You already know what your
kids' names will be.
- 정말?
- 14살 때 골라둔 거야
-You do?
-I had them picked out since I was 14.
설마 과자 이름에서 따온건
아니겠지?
Oh, no, it's gonna be named after
some snack or baked good, isn't it?
- 이름이 뭔데?
- 아들이면 대니얼
-Well, tell us, what are they?
-Okay. If it's a boy, it's Daniel.
- 딸이면?
- 말 안 할래
-And if it's a girl?
-I don't wanna say.
말해, 이름 안 훔쳐갈 테니까
Oh, stop. Tell us.
We're not gonna want it.
좋아, 엠마야
Okay. It's Emma.
엠마
Emma.
봐, 안 훔쳐가잖아
See, I don't want it.
그것만큼이나 딱 어울리는
또 다른 이름 없어?
Do you have any other totally perfect
names that you're not gonna use?
- 네가 써
- 뭐?
-Take it.
-What?
엠마처럼 생겼잖아
She's clearly an Emma.
하지만 네가 좋아하는
이름이잖아
Oh, honey, but you love that name.
그래, 하지만 난 널 더 좋아해
Yeah, but I love you more.
게다가 성이 '빙'인데
뭔 이름인들 어울리겠어
Besides, nothing goes with Bing.
So I'm screwed.
안녕, 엠마
Hi, Emma.
그래, 그게 너야
Yep, that's you.
귀염둥이 엠마
You're our little Em.
뭐라고?
What's that, honey?
뭐?
What?
사촌 동생이 필요해?
Oh, you want a little cousin?
지금 만들어 달라고?
You want a cousin right now?
너희들 눈에도
내가 정자처럼 보여?
Do I look like a giant
sperm to all of you, or..?
'청소 도구실'
- 정말 굉장했어
- 그러게
-That was amazing.
-I know.
이젠 우리 삶이 영원히
달라질 수 있다는 거 알아?
Hey, do you realize that we may have
just changed our lives forever?
가족이 생길지도 모른다고
9개월 후면 우리도 여기서
We may have started our family.
In nine months we could be here..
애를 낳게 될지도 몰라
having our own baby.
어쨌거나 양동이 위에서
해본 건 처음이야
And if not, we got to do it
on a bucket.
너무 사랑해
I love you so much.
- 정말?
- 그럼
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
한 번 더 할래?
You wanna do it again?
그냥 재미로?
This time just for us?
아마도
Probably.
애런 리프만 구랄닉이
미래의 신부에게 인사하고 싶대
Aaron Lipman-Guralnick would like
to say hello to his future bride.
얘가 사람 숨을 막히게 하네
Wow, he kind of takes your breath away,
doesn't he?
예쁘지?
He's a keeper.
이 귀염둥이 좀 보게
Look at the little munchkin.
걱정 마라, 네가 자라서
애런과 데이트할 즘엔
Don't you worry. By the time
you're old enough to date him..
코가 달라져 있을 테니까
he's gonna have a different nose.
- 어때?
- 좋아
-How you feeling?
-Oh, I'm fine.
정말 용감하단 생각이 들어
혼자 애를 키우다니 말야
I really admire what you're doing.
Just raising her all alone.
혼자가 아냐, 로스가 있는걸
I'm not doing it alone. I have Ross.
지금이야 그렇지
하지만 로스가 결혼이라도 하면?
Sure. Now. But what happens when he
meets somebody else and gets married?
다시 이혼하겠지 뭐, 로스잖아
Well, then he gets a divorce.
It's Ross.
진심이니깐, 내 말 들어
I'm telling you, Rachel, listen to Janice.
첨엔 양육하겠다지
자기 가정이 생길 때까지만
They all say they're gonna be there,
until they start their real family.
- 로스는 안 그럴 거야
- 나도 첫 남편을 믿었지
-That's never gonna happen with Ross.
-That's what I thought.
근데 지금은 애를 주말에라도
만나주면 다행이야
I'm lucky if my kid gets to spend
a weekend with her father..
새 풍선 가슴 부인 덕분에
and little Miss New Boobs.
정말?
Really?
이런 얘기하기 싫지만
I hate to be the one to say it..
두 모녀 옆엔 아무도 없는 거야
but, honey, you two are on your own.
글쎄, 그야 뭐...
Well, that's.. You know, that's..
20분간 애랑 단둘이 있었는데
별로 어렵지 않았어
We've been alone for the last
20 minutes and we're doing okay.
게다가 네 말이 틀렸는지도 몰라
Maybe we won't be alone.
왜냐하면 요즘 로스랑 나 사이에
뭔가 진행되고 있거든
Because lately things have been
happening between me and Ross.
진통 시작되기 직전에도
둘이서 키스를 했다고
And right before I went into labor,
we had this kiss. You know?
그게 시작일지도 모르는 거잖아
So it might be the beginning
of something.
- 재니스
- 안녕
-Hey, Janice.
-Oh, hi.
이 신사는 누구야?
Who's this little guy?
- 애런, 네 미래 사위
- 됐어
-Aaron, your future son-in-law.
-Oh, no, no.
됐어
No.
- 그럼 오붓한 시간 보내
- 그래
-I'm gonna leave you three alone.
-Okay.
저 애 코 봤어?
Man, you see the kid on that nose?
내가 뭘 생각하고 있었는지 알아?
You know what I was thinking about?
아파트 출발하기 전에 키스한 거
정말 대단했었지?
That kiss before we left the apartment.
That was something, huh?
그래, 그랬어
Yeah. Yeah, it really was.
그러니 조심해야 돼
But we.. We gotta be careful.
그런 일이 또 생기면 안 되잖아
We.. You know, we can't let
that happen again, you know?
맞아
Right.
- 아닌 길은 나서질 말아야지
- 그럼, 그래서 얘기 꺼낸 거야
-We don't want to go down that road.
-No. That's why I brought it up.
- 병원에 소다수 안 팔아?
- 이런, 미안해
-They didn't have any sodas?
-Oh, my God. I'm sorry.
간호사랑 이야기하다 깜빡했어
I was talking to this nurse.
Completely forgot.
시작됐군
And so it begins.
보여?
She in there?
응, 지금 내려놓는 애가 엠마야
Yeah. She's putting her down now.
That's her.
아기들은 하나같이 예쁘지 않아?
Isn't it amazing how
every baby is beautiful?
얘만 빼고
Except that one.
여기가 동물원이야?
What is this? A petting zoo?
엠마 좀 봐
Look. Look at Emma.
누구를 더 닮았는지 모르겠네
I can't decide who she looks like,
you or Rachel.
농담해? 아주 예쁘잖아!
당연히 레이첼이지
Oh, what, are you kidding?
She's gorgeous! It's all Rachel.
미안한데, 마지막으로 물을게
왜 둘이 결혼 안 한다고?
I'm sorry. For the last time,
why aren't you two together again?
준비가 안 됐다고 했지, 참
No, I know.
Because you're not in that place.
그럴 수 있지, 넌 준비가
다 됐다는 것만 빼면
Which would be fine,
except you totally are.
좀 복잡해, 알았어?
It's complicated, okay?
복잡하지
Yeah, that's true.
넌 늘 레이첼을 사랑했고
이젠 애까지 생겼어
You love her, you always have,
you have a child together.
대책이 없네
There's no right answer.
우린 함께했다 헤어지고
함께했다 다시 헤어지고
Look, we've been together.
Then apart. Then together, then apart.
그러다 애가 생겼어
And now we have a baby.
다시 합쳤다 만약 잘 안 되면...
It's just, if we got together again
and it didn't work out..
엠마한테 그렇겐 못해
I could never do that to Emma.
엠마는 행복할 줄 알고
이 세상에 왔다고, 내 꼴 좀 봐
I mean, she came into this world
thinking everything.. Now me.
이 병원, 물에다가 뭐 섞었대?
What, do they put something
in the water here?
우린 그냥 지금 이대로
아주 잘 지내고 있어
It's just, Rachel and l,
we're doing really well now.
알아, 뭔가 더 바라면
불행이 초래될 수도 있지
I know. If you try to make it more,
you might wreck it.
- 바로 그거야
- 그래
-Yeah, exactly.
-Right.
아님 네가 15살 때부터 원한 걸
모두 가질 수도 있고
Or you might get everything
you've wanted since you were 15.
레이첼
Hey.
어떤 여자가 쌍둥이한테
동시에 모유를 주는데
I saw a woman breast-feeding
twins at the same time.
무슨 서커스 같더라
It is like a freak show up here.
- 왜 그래?
- 아냐
-What's the matter?
-Nothing.
뭔데 그래?
What is it? Hey.
- 아무것도 아냐
- 레이첼, 뭔데?
-Really, it's nothing. I'm..
-Rach, come on. What?
애랑 둘이서 어떻게
살아갈까 생각하고 있었어
I've just been thinking about how
my baby and I are gonna be all alone.
둘이서라니? 로스는 어쩌고?
What are you talking about?
What about Ross?
자기 가족이 생길 텐데 뭐
쌍둥이랑 풍선 가슴 부인이랑
Please. He'll be with his real family.
The twins and little Miss New Boobs.
쳐다보는 거 봤어?
Okay, how long
was I watching that woman?
그러니까 내 말은
I'm just saying that, you know..
언젠가는 로스가 누군가를 만나
someday Ross is gonna
meet somebody..
자기 삶을 갖게 될 거라고
and he's gonna have his own life.
그렇지?
Right?
그러겠지
Yeah, I guess so.
애를 혼자 키우는 생각은
해본 적이 없어
I just never thought I'd be raising
this baby all by myself.
바보 같지?
That's pretty dumb, huh?
내 말 잘 들어
Hey, you listen to me. Listen to me.
혼자 있는 일은 절대로 없을 거야
You are never, ever gonna be alone.
그런 일 없을 거라고 약속할게
Okay? I promise
I won't let that happen.
고마워, 네가 있어서 다행이야
Joey. Oh, sweetie,
what would I do without you?
그런 걱정은 하지 마
You don't have to worry about that,
okay?
티슈 상자 좀 줄래?
Could you grab me my other box
of tissues?
- 로스 코트 밑에 있어
- 그래
-They're under Ross' coat.
-Sure.
맙소사!
Oh, my God!
조이?
Joey?
맙소사
Oh, my God.
좋아
Okay.